Henrique Ferreira

Frontend/Web Developer

As a Graphic Designer who dared to venture into the world of coding, I discovered a newfound passion and love for the art of web development. Nowadays, I am an experienced and qualified Front-end Engineer who loves to develop projects that provides a great user experiences. With an open mind to all possibilities of learning, I am motivated by the challenges that push me to expand my knowledge and skills, which ultimately allow me to become an even more valuable asset to any organization. I pride myself on being punctual, assiduous, and responsible, while also being a very communicative and quick learner.

Professional experience

2017 – 2022 ForDesign SC Web Developer

- Develop and manage websites using WordPress, Prestashop, Shopify and ReactJs.
 (HTML, CSS, JS, TypeScript , ReactJs, jOuery, PHP, Sass, Boostrap, Git, NPM e Figma)
- Built and delivered technical solutions according to stakeholder business requirements.
- Produce newsletters and design layouts for mobile apps. (HTML, CSS, Illustrator, Photoshop e Figma)
- Develop custom WordPress themes and plugins to cater to unique client needs. (HTML, css, Js e PHP)
- Customize layouts for WordPress, Prestashop, and Shopify to enhance website usability and user experience. (HTML, CSS, JS, PHP e Liquid)
- Collaborate with designers, project managers, and other engineers to transform creative concepts into production realities for clients and stakeholders.
- Work alongside creative directors to lead the research, development, and architecture of technical solutions to fulfill business requirements.
- Provide leadership within engineering department through close collaboration, knowledge shares, and mentorship.

2016 – 2017 Conceitos Diferentes Web Designer

- Develop and manage websites to ensure optimal functionality and user experience. (HTML, CSS, JS, TypeScript, ReactJs, jQuery, PHP, Sass, Boostrap, Git, NPM e Figma)
- Design, develop and edit advertising projects, including photos and videos. (Photoshop, After Effects e Premiere)
- Prepare posts for newspapers, magazines, billboards, ads, banners, and other media. (Corel Draw Illustrator, Photoshop e Indesign)
- Design newsletter layouts to enhance readability and visual appeal (HTML, CSS, Illustrator, Photoshop e Figma)
- Built and delivered technical solutions according to stakeholder business requirements.
- Work alongside creative directors to lead the research, development, and architecture of technical solutions to fulfill business requirements.

- Create, develop, and edit presentations in multiple languages for state leaders, executives, committees, and foreign delegations.
- Develop strategic and visually appealing pieces and public relations campaigns related to the government's actions in the House of Representatives.
- Manage websites using HTML and CSS to ensure optimal functionality and user experience
- Create and design newsletter diagrams and programs to enhance readability and visual appeal

2011 – 2013 Seven CGI 🚳 Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop and InDesign Trainer

- Instruct students on the fundamental principles of graphic and web design.
- Teach students to use Adobe Creative Suite software, including Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Dreamweaver, Flash, and Corel Draw.
- Develop and deliver engaging lesson plans and instructional materials to facilitate student learning and retention.

Education

2013 — 2015	MBA - Business Management Universidade do Grande Rio • Brazil
2011 — 2013	Higher Education in Marketing Faculdade Gama e Souza • Brazil
2008 – 2012	Graphic and Web Design Seven Computação Gráfico • Brazil
2008 — 2010	High School

Guimarães - Portugal

+351 927 600 909

henrique.f.dutra@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/hfdutra

(instagram.com/henrique_ferreira

Based in Portugual since 2016

Skills

HTML	
CSS	
PHP	
Javascript	
SASS	
Tailwind	
Bootstrap	
React	
NextJs	
Git	
Gulp	
jQuery	
NPM	
WebPack	
WordPress	
Shopify	
Prestashop	
Figma	
Adobe Illustrator	
Adobe Photoshop	
Adobe InDesign	

Courses

2022	Front-end Engineer
2021	Wordpress Developer
2020	PHP to Wordpress
2016	Art Direction
2015	Digital Marketing

Languages

Portuguese - Native
English - Advanced
Spanish - Work knowledge